Ortenilton S. Filho

Department of Mathematics University of Coimbra 3000-143 Coimbra, Portugal

orteniltonfilho@gmail.com https://ortenilton.github.io/ortenilton-website/

Research interests

My research interests currently focus on the analysis of partial differential equations, more specifically on the exploration of results in the core of the theory of viscosity solutions. Recently, my efforts have turned to the study of fractional vanishing viscosity and numerical methods for this context.

Education

Oct 2023 - Present

Ph.D. in Mathematics

Universidade de Coimbra - UC

Title: TBA

Advised by: Edgard Pimentel and Ercília Sousa

Aug 2021 - Aug 2023

M.Sc. in Mathematics

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro - PUC-Rio

Title: Estimativas Aleksandrov-Bakelman-Pucci Advised by: Boyan Sirakov and Gustavo Araújo

Jun 2017 - Jul 2021

B.Sc. in Mathematics

Universidade Federal de Sergipe - UFS

Title: Estudo Introdutório da Teoria Lagrageana e Teoria Hamiltoniana com

Aplicações a Osciladores Paramétricos

Advised by: Gerson Araujo

Previous positions

Nov 2020 - Feb 2021

Teaching assistant, Real Analysis

Department of Mathematics, Universidade Federal de Sergipe, Brazil

Aug 2020 - Jul 2021

Research Projects

Estabilidade Paramétrica do Pêndulo com Suspensão Variável

Universidade Federal de Sergipe, Brazil

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

Mentoring Activity

REVIMAT: Revisão de Conteúdos Matemáticos

Universidade Federal de Sergipe, Brazil

Feb 2020 - May 2020 Mentoring Activity

REVIMAT: Revisão de Conteúdos Matemáticos

Universidade Federal de Sergipe, Brazil

Aug 2019 - Jul 2020 Research Projects

Estabilidade Linear do Pêndulo Simples Universidade Federal de Sergipe, Brazil

Apr 2019 - Jul 2019 Research Projects

Aritmética computacional

Universidade Federal de Sergipe, Brazil

List of publications

Papers published in scientific journals

 Estudo analítico do problema restrito dos três corpos Studies in Engineering and Exact Sciences, (2023) w/ Gerson Cruz and Clésio Carlos

Honors and awards

Oct 2022 - Present — FAPERJ Fellowship Mestrado Nota 10

Fundação Carlos Chagas Filho de Amparo à Pesquisa do Estado do Rio de

Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro

Fellowships

Aug 2021 - Sep 2022 Master Fellowship

Coordenação de Aperfeiçoamento de Pessoal de Nível Superior - CAPES

Aug 2020 - Jul 2021 Cientific Initiation Fellowship

Coordenação de Pesquisa - COPES

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020 Mentoring Activity

Pró-Reitoria de Graduação - PROGRAD

Feb 2020 - May 2020 Mentoring Activity

Pró-Reitoria de Graduação - PROGRAD

Advanced schools and training

Jan 2023 - Mar 2023 -	Summer course in Differential Topology Instituto de Matemática Pura e Aplicada - IMPA, Brazil
Mar 2022	Fortaleza Conference on Analysis and PDEs (Virtual Meeting) Universidade Federal do Ceará - UFC, Brazil
Dec 2021	Escuela Matemática de América Latina y el Caribe (Virtual Meeting) Universidad Juárez Autónoma de Tabasco - UJAT, Mexico
Jan 2021	Introdução à dinâmica epidemiológica (Virtual Meeting) Universidade de Brasília - UnB, Brazil
Jan 2021- Feb 2021 —	Summer course in Real Analisys (Virtual) Instituto de Matemática Pura e Aplicada - IMPA, Brazil
Jan 2021 - Feb 2021 -	Summer course in Real Analisys Universidade Federal de Sergipe - UFS, Brazil

Participations in events

Jan 2023 - Feb 2023 -	Programa de Verão Instituto de Matemática Pura e Aplicada - IMPA, Brazil
Oct 2021	XXI Semana de Matemática - A Matemática e suas conexões com o Ensino Fundamental e Médio Universidade Federal de Rondônia-Câmpus de Ji-Paraná - UNIR-JP, Brazil
Jan 2021- Feb 2021 —	Programa de Verão (Virtual) Instituto de Matemática Pura e Aplicada - IMPA, Brazil

Jan 2021 - Feb 2021 -	X Escola de Verão em Matemática Universidade Federal de Sergipe - UFS, Brazil
Nov 2020	30° Encontro de Iniciação Científica Universidade Federal de Sergipe - UFS, Brazil
Sep 2020 ———	XX Semana de Matemática - Matemática e algumas de suas ramificações: Matemática Pura, Matemática Aplicada e Educação Matemática. tudo junto e misturado? Universidade Federal de Rondônia-Câmpus de Ji-Paraná - UNIR-JP, Brazil
Jan 2020 - Mar 2020 -	IX Escola de Verão em Matemática Universidade Federal de Sergipe - UFS, Brazil
Nov 2019	29º Encontro de Iniciação Científica Universidade Federal de Sergipe - UFS, Brazil
Nov 2019	7th Workshop on Analysis in PDEs Universidade Federal de Sergipe - UFS, Brazil
Nov 2018	6th Workshop on Analysis in PDEs Universidade Federal de Sergipe - UFS, Brazil